Guide to the Joshua Lederberg Papers SC0186
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Joshua Lederberg papers
1959-1979
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Lederberg, Joshua
SC0186
22 Linear Feet
Papers consist of Lederberg's administrative files while head of the department of genetics at Stanford University Medical School from 1959 to 1978; they are divided into five series. 1) General files, 1959-77, pertain to miscellaneous University and Medical School committees and matters including computer systems, curriculum, and research proposals. 2) Minutes, agenda, and memos from the Stanford Medical School Executive Committee, 1959-78. 3) Agenda, memos, and subject folders from the Stanford University Committee on Research, 1966-78, including topics such as conflict of interest, defense research, human subjects, and patents. 4) Plans, proposals, and equipment specifications for the Clinical Sciences Research Building, 1960-66. 5) Personnel files on people under consideration for appointment to the SUMS faculty, 1962-78. Papers added to the collection since 1978 pertain to a SWOPSI course on the environmental impact on health taught by David P. Sachs, 1970; two Stanford academic programs: United States-China Relations, 1973-78, and Arms Control and Disarmament, 1971-78; and the genetics department.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Joshua Lederberg, 1978-2000.
Information about Access
Partially restricted: personnel and search files are restricted.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Lederberg earned his Ph.D. at Yale University in 1947. He taught genetics at the University of Wisconsin before coming to the Stanford University School of Medicine in 1959 as Professor of genetics and biology.
Description of the Collection
Papers consist of Lederberg's administrative files while head of the department of genetics at Stanford University Medical School from 1959 to 1978; they are divided into five series. 1) General files, 1959-77, pertain to miscellaneous University and Medical School committees and matters including computer systems, curriculum, and research proposals. 2) Minutes, agenda, and memos from the Stanford Medical School Executive Committee, 1959-78. 3) Agenda, memos, and subject folders from the Stanford University Committee on Research, 1966-78, including topics such as conflict of interest, defense research, human subjects, and patents. 4) Plans, proposals, and equipment specifications for the Clinical Sciences Research Building, 1960-66. 5) Personnel files on people under consideration for appointment to the SUMS faculty, 1962-78. Papers added to the collection since 1978 pertain to a SWOPSI course on the environmental impact on health taught by David P. Sachs, 1970; two Stanford academic programs: United States-China Relations, 1973-78, and Arms Control and Disarmament, 1971-78; and the genetics department.
Environmental health.; Lederberg, Joshua; Stanford University. Arms Control and Disarmament Program; Lederberg, Joshua; Stanford University. United States-China Relations Program; Stanford University. Computation Center; Stanford University. School of Medicine; Stanford University. School of Medicine. Curriculum; Stanford University. Committee on Research; Stanford University. School of Medicine. Faculty; Stanford University. School of Medicine. Executive Committee; Sachs, David P.
- General Files, Series 1
  - Academic Information Center, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Action Reserve Liaison Office (ARLO), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Affirmative Action, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alway, R. H., 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Attitudes of Palo Alto Toward Stanford, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Basic Medical Sciences Committee, general, 1959-65 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Basic Medical Sciences Committee, 1971, 1974, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Basic Medical Sciences Planning Committee, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Basic Medical Sciences Planning Committee, 1971, 1974, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Biochemistry Department, 1960-62 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Biohazard Control Committee, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Biology, 1961-63 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Biomedical Engineering Committee, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Biophysics Department, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Biophysics Laboratory, list of publications and papers, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bookstore, Stanford, information about faculty services and usage of the bookstore, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Budget and Program Review Committee (BURR), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - BURR, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Campaign for Stanford, PACE program, faculty volunteer group, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Cancer Biology, program in, 12/1977 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Cardiac Surgery, 1973-74 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Cardiovascular and Respiratory: Research, proposal for, V. 1, pt. 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cardiovascular and Respiratory: Research, proposal for, V. 1, pt. 2 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cardiovascular and Respiratory: Research, proposal for, V. 2, pt. 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cardiovascular and Respiratory: Research, proposal for, V. 2, pt. 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cellular and Molecular Biology Training Committee, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Clinical Research Center Committee, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Commonwealth Fund, correspondence with regarding the establishment of the Stanford University Medical School, 1954-59 (1 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Commonwealth Fund, correspondence with regarding the establishment of the Stanford University Medical School, 1954-59 (2 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Commonwealth Fund, correspondence with regarding the establishment of the Stanford University Medical School, 1954-59 (3 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Commonwealth Fund, correspondence with regarding the establishment of the Stanford University Medical School, 1954-59 (4 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Computation Center, Facilities Committee, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Computation Center, Facilities Committee, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Computation Center, Facilities Committee, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Computation Center, Facilities Committee, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Computation Center, Facilities Committee, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Computation Center, Facilities Committee, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Computation Center, Facilities Committee, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Computation Center, Facilities Committee, 1974-75 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Computation Center, Facilities Committee, 1974-75 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Computation Center, Facilities Committee, 1974-75 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Computation Center, Facilities Committee, Memos, 1967-68 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Computer Committee, Provost’s, 5/1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Computer Science Department, faculty memos, 1975-76 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Computer System Planning, Report of the President’s Committee, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Courses and Curriculum, Committee on, 1962-69 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Courses and Curriculum, manual, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum and Courses, Committee on, general, 1956-1961 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Curriculum and Courses, Committee on, general, 1961-1969 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum and Courses, Interim Committee on, 1968-69 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Curriculum and Courses, Committee on, minutes, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Curriculum and Courses, Committee on, minutes, 1960-61 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Ecology House, Stanford, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Engineering, School of, Advisory Council, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Engineering, School of, Advisory Council, meeting, 2/23 - 24/78 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Engineering, School of, Dean Kays, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Engineering, School of, Five-year plan, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Engineering, School of, Five-year plan, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Faculty Senate of Stanford University Medical School (SUMS), agenda, minutes, 1960, 1962, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Federman Committee for SUMS faculty appointments and promotions, 1974 - 75 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - SUMS: Medical School Faculty Handbook (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Genetics Research Center, Proposal for, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Health Services Administration (HSA), description of academic position, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - HSA, Program and References, 1973-76 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - HSA, Program and References, 1973-76 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Health Services Research Committee, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - HSA, selection of outlines for a course in policy analysis, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - HSA, selection of outlines for a course in policy analysis, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - HSA, selection of outlines for a course in policy analysis, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Heart, Lung, Blood Center, Committee on, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Human Development, Department of, proposal, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Information Retrieval, Faculty Advisory Committee on, 5/16/68 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Interdisciplinary Research, Stanford Center for, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Manning Committee, Law/Euphonics, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Medical Education Committee, 1966-67 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Medical Education Committee II, 1966-67 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Medical Information System (MIS), Lockheed, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Medical Mathematics, Statistics, and Data Analysis, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Medical Microbiology, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Medical Service Plan (MSP), Executive Committee, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Medicine, School of, Administrative Committee, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Medicine, School of, Administrative Committee, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Medicine, School of, Administrative Committee, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Medicine, School of, Committee, funding, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Medicine, School of, Facilities Planning, minutes, 1958 - 59 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Medicine, School of, History, before 1959 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Medicine, School of, History, 1956 and n.d. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Medicine, School of, Committee on Human Nutrition, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Neurological Sciences Department, Ad Hoc Committee, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Pediatrics, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Pediatrics, Advisory Committee, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Planning and Development, Trustee’s Committee on, 1969-70 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Public Policy, Committee on, January, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Center for Information Processing, (SCIP), 1973 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Study of Education at Stanford (SES), 1967 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - SES, 1967-69 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - SES, Committee on Computer Problems, 1965-68 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Study of Medical Education at Stanford (SMES), 1972 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - SMES, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - SMES, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Undergraduate Studies at Stanford, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - University Policy, Committee on, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - University Policy, Committee on, 1962-63 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Stanford University Medical Center Executive Committee, Series 2
  - 1959-60 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - 1960-61 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - 1961-62 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - 1962-63 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - 1963-65 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - 1963-65 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - 7/23/1965 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - 11/19/1965 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Agenda, 1966-67 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - 1/27/1966 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - 1967-68 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - 9/15/1967 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - 10/20/1967 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - 2/16/1968 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 3/15/1968 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 5/17/68, 7/19/68 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 9/20/1968 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 11/15/1968 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - 12/20/1968 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - 2/19/1969 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - 4/18/1969 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - 5/16/1969 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - 10/17/1969 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - 1969 Dec (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - 2/20/1970 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - 3/20/1970 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - 4/17/1970 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - 5/15/1970 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - 6/19/1970 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - 7/17/1970 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 9/18/1970 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 10/9/70, 10/13/70 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - 11/3/1970 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - 11/13/1970 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - 12/11/1970 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - 12/18/1970 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 1/22/1971 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 2/19/1971 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - 3/5/1971 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - 3/19/1971 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - 4/13/1971 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - 4/21/1971 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - 5/7/1971 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - 5/19/1971 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - 6/18/1971 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - 7/16/1971 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - 9/17/1971 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - 10/15/1971 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - 11/19/1971 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - 12/1/1971 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - 12/17/1971 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Regional Medical Programs, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - 1/21/1972 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - 2/18/1972 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - 3/7/1972 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - 3/24/1972 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - 4/7/1972 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - 4/21/1972 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - 5/5/1972 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - 5/19/1972 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - 6/1/1972 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - 6/16/1972 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - 7/7/1972 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - 10/6/1972 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - 10/24/1972 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - 11/10/1972 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - 12/15/1972 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - 1972 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - 1/26/1973 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - 2/2/1973 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - 2/16/1973 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - 3/12/1973 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - 3/30/1973 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - 4/20/1973 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - 5/4/1973 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - 5/18/1973 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - 6/12/1973 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - 6/22/1973 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - 7/20/1973 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Policy Statement, 8/1/73 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - 9/21/1973 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - 10/12/1973 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - 11/16/1973 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - 11/30/1973 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - 12/7/1973 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - 12/14/1973 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - 1973 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - 1/4/1974 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - 1/25/1974 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - 2/5/1974 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - 2/15/1974 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - 2/22/1974 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - 3/1/1974 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - 3/8/1974 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - 3/15/1974 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - 4/5/1974 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - 4/19/1974 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - 5/10/1974 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - 5/10/1974 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - 5/17/1974 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - 6/14/1974 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - 7/19/1974 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - 8/5/1974 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - 9/20/1974 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - 10/19/1974 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - 10/25/1974 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - 11/8-9/74 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - 12/6/1974 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - 12/20/1974 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Affirmative Action, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - 1974 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - 1/7/75, 1/24/75 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - 2/21/1975 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - 3/7/1975 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - 3/21/1975 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - 4/4/1975 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - 4/18/1975 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - 5/16/1975 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - 6/20/1975 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - 7/25/1975 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - 8/22/1975 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - 9/19/1975 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - 9/20/1975 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - 10/24/1975 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - 11/14/1975 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - 1975 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum Studies, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - 1/9/1976 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - 1/23/1976 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - 2/20/1976 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - 3/19/1976 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - 4/16/1976 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - 5/7/1976 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - 5/21/1976 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - 6/18/1976 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - 7/2/1976 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - 7/16/1976 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - 9/24/1976 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - 10/15/1976 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - 11/5/1976 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - 12/17/1976 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - 1976 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - 1976 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - 1/21/1977 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - 2/18/1977 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - 3/18/1977 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - 6/17/1977 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - 8/3/1977 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - 8/12/1977 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - 8/19/1977 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - 9/2/1977 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - 9/23/1977 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - 10/21/1977 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - 12/16/1977 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - 1977 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - 1/27/1978 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - 2/17/1978 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - 3/17/1978 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - 4/21/1978 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - 5/5/1978 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - 5/19/1978 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - 1978 (Box 19, Folder 21)
- Stanford University Committee on Research, Series 3
  - Records, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Records, 1969-70 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Records, 8/70 (Box 20A, Folder 1)
  - Records, 9/70 (Box 20A, Folder 2)
  - Records, 10/70 (Box 20A, Folder 3)
  - Records, 11/70 (Box 20A, Folder 4)
  - Records, 12/70 (Box 20A, Folder 5)
  - Records, 1/71 (Box 20A, Folder 6)
  - Records, 2/71 (Box 20B, Folder 7)
  - Records, 3/71 (Box 20B, Folder 8)
  - Records, 3/18/71 (Box 20B, Folder 9)
  - Records, 4/71 (Box 20B, Folder 10)
  - Records, 5/71 (Box 20B, Folder 11)
  - Records, 5/17/71 (Box 20B, Folder 12)
  - Records, 6/71 (Box 20B, Folder 13)
  - Records, 7/71 (Box 20B, Folder 14)
  - Records, 9/71-12/71 (Box 20B, Folder 15)
  - Records, 1972 (Box 21A, Folder 1)
  - Records, 1973 (Box 21A, Folder 2)
  - Academic Council, 1970-73 (Box 21A, Folder 3)
  - Administration, 1971 (Box 21A, Folder 4)
  - Administration, 1971 (Box 21A, Folder 5)
  - Cancer Research Center Planning Committee, 1971-72 (Box 21B, Folder 6)
  - Cancer Research Center Planning Committee, 1971-72 (Box 21B, Folder 7)
  - Cancer Research Center Planning Committee, 1973-74 (Box 21B, Folder 8)
  - Conflict of Interest, 1966-1972 (Box 21B, Folder 9)
  - Contract Clauses, 1969 (Box 22A, Folder 1)
  - Defense Research, 1970 (Box 22A, Folder 2)
  - DOD, 1970 (Box 22A, Folder 3)
  - Human subject, 1966-71 (Box 22A, Folder 4)
  - Indirect Costs, 1970-71 (Box 22A, Folder 5)
  - Mansfield, Fulbright, 1969 (Box 22B, Folder 6)
  - Membership, 1969 (Box 22B, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969-70 (Box 22B, Folder 8)
  - New Directions in Research, 1969 (Box 22B, Folder 9)
  - Organizations, n.d. (Box 22B, Folder 10)
  - Patents, 1970 (Box 22B, Folder 11)
  - Patents, 1970 (Box 22B, Folder 12)
  - Report, 5/1970 (Box 22B, Folder 13)
  - Report to the Academic Senate, 1970 (Box 23A, Folder 1)
  - Research Associates, 1970 (Box 23A, Folder 2)
  - Student Initiated Research, 1969-1970 (Box 23A, Folder 3)
  - Study Projects, 1969 (Box 23A, Folder 4)
- Clinical Sciences Research Building, Series 4
  - Blank Building, Common Facilities, 1962-66 (Box 23A, Folder 5)
  - Architectural Designs (Box 25)
  - Blank Building Preliminary Study, Stage A. 1961-62 (Box 23A, Folder 6)
  - Architectural Designs (Box 26)
  - Blank Building, Stage B, 1961-62 (Box 23A, Folder 7)
  - Blank Building, Stage C, 1962 (Box 23A, Folder 8)
  - Blank Building, Stage D, 1962-64 (Box 23A, Folder 9)
  - Blank Building, Stage D, 1962-64 (Box 23B, Folder 10)
  - Building File, 1960-62 (Box 23B, Folder 11)
  - Equipment specifications, 1965, Group II (Box 23B, Folder 12)
  - Equipment specifications, 1965, Group III (Box 23B, Folder 13)
  - Equipment specifications, 1965, Group III (Box 24A, Folder 1)
  - Planning Information for Gorsline, 1962 (Box 24A, Folder 2)
  - Space Program, 1964-1965 (Box 24B, Folder 3)
- Restricted Files, Series 5
  - Search Committee Files (Box 27-35)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1999-058
  - Materials pertaining to David Sachs (Lederberg was faculty sponsor for Sachs' SWOPSI course "Environmental Impact on Health" 1970)
    - "Ecology and Democracy: Regional Environmental Regulation in the San Francisco Bay Area" by Stephen P. Fortmann, and Sachs' comments on, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "Importance of Open Space and a Case Study of the Palo Alto-Stanford Area" by Carol Christensen and Rick Johnson, and Sachs' comments on, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Noise Pollution in the United States" by Mark Clark, comments on, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "Sewage Treatment and Pollution: Monterey Bay, June 1970" by Joseph Welsch, Adrian Arima and Daniel Green and Sachs' comments on, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Sachs, David - correspondence file 1969-78 (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Sachs, David - correspondence file 1969-78 (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Sachs, David - correspondence file 1969-78 (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Sachs, David - grant application for "Effect of High Oxygen Exposure on Cellular Membranes," 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Mass Media and the Environment. Volume 1: San Francisco and Monterey Bay Water Resources. September 1971. Project directors: David Peter Sachs and David Mark Rubin. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Mass Media and the Environment. Volume 3: A Guide to Information Sources in the San Francisco Bay Area. September 1971. Project directors: David Peter Sachs and David Mark Rubin. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Politics of Pollution Control in Monterey Bay by Joseph Welsch, Adrian Arima and Dan Green. A Stanford Workshop on Political and Social Issues and Environmental Research Project Publication. September 1971. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Papers of Lederberg/Dept. of Genetics
    - D.O.D. Sponsored Research at Stanford. Volume 1. Two Perceptions: The Investigator's and the Sponsor's. A report by the Stanford Workshop on Political and Social Issues. June 1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Goldsmith, Joseph Lary, " Health Hazards of the Pollution of San Francisco Bay." Class paper from Human Biology March 1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Job openings at other institutions, incoming correspondence 1971-78 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Kallman, Robert F. Cancer biology training program - grant application and related correspondence, 1977-78 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Report of the Professional Women of Stanford Medical School, December 1969, and related correspondence, 1969-75 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Study of the University Role in Engineering Research for NASA Particularized to the Stanford University Case. Prepared by the School of Engineering, Stanford University, June 25, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Zale, Morris P. and Zale Foundation, clippings and correspondence re, 1968-69 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - RESTRICTED PAPERS (mostly personnel and recommendation files)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Restricted 75 years from date of creation
    - Job applications - postdoctoral, A - K (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bodmer, Walter (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Buchanan, Bruce (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Cann, Howard (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Katchadourian, Herant (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Kessler, Seymour (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Kornberg, Roger (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Levine, Seymour (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Levinthal, Elliott (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Macovski, Albert (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Melmon, Kenneth Lloyd (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Michaels, Alan S. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Miller, Warren (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Mishell, Daniel (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Nelson, Bernard (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Ogunmola, G. B. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Rindfleisch, tom (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Ross, Russell (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Rubenstein, Ed (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Sachs, David (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Schulman, Irving (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Schwab, Leslie (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Schimke, Robert (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Short, Elizabeth M. (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Siegel, Alberta (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Simons, Richard (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Smith, Dennis (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Stryker, L. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Tarjan, R. (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Weiner, Norman (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Wilkinson, David (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Zalut, Clyde (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Restricted file from accn 2002-022: A. T. Ganesan (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1999-141
  Restricted 75 years from date of creation.
  - Human Biology 102, 1972-1976
    - Student files (Box 1)